# THOMAS ARCHBOLD

32 Purbrook Estate, Tower Bridge Road, London, SE1 3BZ tomjarchbold@gmail.com  $\diamond +44~7837~674~419 \diamond$  tomarchbold.com

#### BACKGROUND

I am a Ph.D. candidate at King's College London where I am part of the Distributed Artificial Intelligence group. My research interests are in algorithmic game theory and mechanism design, as well as other areas of theoretical computer science including algorithms and complexity theory.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Ph.D. Computer Science, King's College London

2020-2024 (expected)

Research interests: algorithmic game theory and mechanism design, bounded rationality, theoretical computer science

Supervisor: Professor Carmine Ventre

MSc. Computer Science, University of Warwick

2019-2020

Classification: Distinction

Dissertation title: A Decentralised Peer-Prediction Market (awarded distinction)

BSc. (Hons) Computer Science, University of Warwick

2016-2019

Classification: 2-1

Dissertation title: An Educational Kernel for the Raspberry Pi (awarded first class)

## EXPERIENCE

## Graduate Teaching Assistant, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

6CCS3OME Optimization Methods

2021/22, 2020/21

- 4CCS1DST Data Structures

2021/22

**Private Tutor** Oct 2020-present

Tutor privately for maths and computer science from GCSE up to undergraduate level. Provide guidance for writing personal statements and deliver mock interviews for university admissions.

# Software Graphics Engineer Intern, Imagination Technologies, Kings Langley

Jul 2019-Sep 2019

Worked with the PowerVR Vulkan driver team researching Google's ANGLE API to analyse its performance on the driver, and wrote OpenGLES and Vulkan programs to test specific areas of its functionality. Contributed driver code and discussed progress and plans in weekly team meetings.

#### ACADEMIC INVOLVEMENT

Seminar Organiser, Distributed Artificial Intelligence group, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

Help to organise the fortnightly seminar within the Distributed Artificial Intelligence research group, which involves contacting internal and external speakers to present talks on their work and chairing the meetings.

## Conference Volunteer

- International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP)

Jul 2021

## Sub-reviewer

- Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT)

Jun 2021

## Poster presenter, International Conference for Undergraduate Research 2018

Sep 2018

Presented individual research project on "Cellular Automata and Computational Universality" at the ICUR. Produced an introductory primer on cellular automata and their applications plus visualisation software.

#### LANGUAGES AND SKILLS

**Programming Languages** Languages

Bash, C, Common Lisp, Python French (B2/upper intermediate)

Russian (B1/intermediate)

## WIDER ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

King's Education Awards Nominee

2021

First XV Player of the Season, University of Warwick RFC

2019/20, 2018/19

UWRFC First XV, QE Boys Rugby First XV, QE Boys Cricket First XI

2016-20, 2014-16, 2015-16